NAVEEN N RAVI

250 East 6th Street, Apt 0804 \$\infty\$ Saint Paul, MN 55101

(832) · 720 · 2393 ♦ https://naveen-rn.github.io/ ♦ nravi.research@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Professional Software Engineer with experience in the general areas of parallel and distributed computing. Specifically, my technical skills focuses in the following areas: (i) distributed parallel programming models and runtime systems for HPC (MPI and OpenSHMEM) and ML (NCCL/RCCL); (ii) parallel computing architectures, and (iii) high-speed network interconnects (HPE Slingshot and Infiniband).

EXPERIENCE

Hewlett Packard Enterprise (previously Cray, Inc)

Jan, 2016 - present

Senior Systems/Software Engineer

Bloomington, MN

- · HPC and ML communication runtime optimizations for HPE/Cray supercomputers and clusters
- · Tech Lead for Cray programming environment software stacks including Cray MPI and Cray SHMEM
- · Participate and represent HPE/Cray in OpenSHMEM and MPI standards committee

May,2015 - Dec,2015 Cray, Inc InternSaint Paul, MN

- · Research and prototype new communication protocols in Cray SHMEM library
- · Optimize Global Arrays library for NAMD and NWChem Chemistry applications

University of Houston

Sep,2013 - May,2015

Research Assistant - HPC Tools

Houston, TX

- · Research Assistant to Prof. Barbara Chapman
- · Explore strategies for communication runtime optimizations for scalable parallel systems

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities

Aug, 2022 - Present

Ph.D. in Computer Science

University of Houston, Main Campus

Auq,2013 - Dec,2015

M.S. in Computer Science - Specialization in Parallel & Distributed Systems

Anna University, India

Sep,2007 - May,2011

Bachelors in Engineering - Electrical & Electronics Engineering

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages

Parallel Programming Models & Libraries

Network Libraries

System Architectures

Architectures

C/C++, Python

OpenSHMEM, MPI, NCCL/RCCL, Coarray Fortran

Libfabric, UCX, Verbs

Aarch64, x86_64, GPU

HPE Cray Supercomputers & Clusters